Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin American presidential collection, 1775-2009.
Rudin, Gail and Stephen American presidential collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gail and Stephen Rudin American presidential collection, 1775-2009.
6844
Stephen, Rudin
6 Cubic Feet.
Correspondence, Memorabilia, Newspapers, Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Historical letters, documents and ephemera relating to American presidential campaigns from Abraham Lincoln to Barack Obama.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Historical letters, documents and ephemera relating to American presidential campaigns from Abraham Lincoln to Barack Obama. Newspapers include issues of the New York Times from Nov. 23-26, 1963, focusing on the assassination of President Kennedy and its aftermath.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rudin, Stephen,; Kennedy, John F. -- (John Fitzgerald), -- 1917-1963 -- Assassination.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Other Presidential letters can be found in the Frank Thilly Papers, #14-21-623, Wilson, Taft; Johnson family papers, #4928, Adams; Jared Sparks Collection of Autographs, #4600 Bd. Ms. 548 ++, Washington.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Abraham Lincoln
Documents
Letters, Envelopes, and Postcards
Ribbons, Badges, Medals, and Tokens
Songs
Miscellaneous Objects
Newspapers
Series II. Other U.S. Presidents (alphabetic)
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Abraham Lincoln
  - Documents
    - Lincoln, Abraham Office held: As U.S. Representative from Illinois, 5/22/1849; Physical description: Bound volume
      Lincoln's patent to lift boats over shoals, written while Lincoln served as a representative in the Illinois legislature. See separated materials below.
      Rudin # L-1
    - Lincoln, Abraham Office held: As President Writer's location: Washington D.C., September 26, 1862; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General Orders No. 141: Suspension of Habeas Corpus.
      Rudin # L-1C
    - Lincoln, Abraham Office held: As President Writer's location: Washington D.C., April 16, 1863; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 2)
      General Orders No. 89: Dishonorable dismissal of Lt. J.M. Garland.
      Rudin # L-1B
    - Lincoln, Abraham Office held: As President Writer's location: Washington D.C., July 31, 1863; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 3)
      General Orders No. 252: Order threatening the execution of prisoners.
      Rudin # L-1D
    - Meade, Gen. George and Ruggles, Gen. George Writer's location: Headquarters of the Army of the Potomoc, April 16, 17, 1865; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
      General Orders No. 15 and No. 16: Announcements of Lincoln's death and the details of official mourning ceremonies.
      Rudin # L-1A
  - Letters, Envelopes, and Postcards
    - Envelope, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Envelope advertising the Lincoln-Hamlin campaign of 1860, depicting beardless Lincoln splitting rails.
      Rudin # L-4A
    - Parks, Samuel C. Writer's location: Lincoln, Illinois Addressee: Robert B. Lantham, February 27, 1861; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Letter describing Lincoln's nighttime trip into Washington to avoid assassination after his election. Sent from Lincoln, Ill.
      Rudin # L-2B
    - "William" Writer's location: Metropolitan Hotel, Washington D.C. Addressee: My dear Mother, September 4, 1863; 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Letter describing a visit with Lincoln in the Oval Office.
      Rudin # L-2
    - Envelope, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Envelope advertising the Lincoln-Johnson campaign of 1864, with jugate images of candidates in profile.
      Rudin # L-4B
    - Envelopes, between 1861 and 1865; 5 envelopes (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Series of envelopes with political cartoons of Lincoln and Jefferson Davis fighting a boxing match.
      Rudin # L-4E
    - Postcards, between 1861 and 1865; 19 postcards (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Postcards depicting the Lincoln Memorial in Washington, D.C.
      Rudin # L-5
    - Postcards, between 1861 and 1865; 3 postcards (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Postcards related to the Gettysburg Address.
      Rudin # L-5A
    - Envelope, between 1861 and 1865 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Civil War envelope, depicting a hand-colored image of beardless Lincoln.
      Rudin # L-4C
    - Envelope, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Envelope for 1860 campaign, depicting beardless Lincoln and topped with a liberty cap between flags.
      Rudin # L-4D
    - Leaming, James Writer's location: Bridgeton, N.J. Addressee: Reuben Learning (writer's brother), April 17, 1865; 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Letter discussing the death of Lincoln and what it means to the country. Sent from Bridgeton, N.J.
      Rudin # L-2C
    - "James" Addressee: My dear Wife, April 17, 21, 1865; 2 letters, 4 pages total (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Letters giving first-hand accounts of events just after Lincoln's assassination.
      Rudin # L-2A
    - Envelope Writer's location: Cincinnati, OH Addressee: James G. Barnwell, May 31, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Envelope printed with mourning cover and portrait in honor of Lincoln's death.
      Rudin # L-4
    - Envelope, 1963, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 16A)
      5 Envelopes commemorating the 100th and 150th anniversary of the Emancipation Proclamation, with stamps
    - Envelope, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 16B)
      Envelope commemorating 85th anniversary of the Gettysburg Address, with stamp
    - Postcards, 7 postcards (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Postcards related to Lincoln's assassination.
      Rudin # L-5B
    - Postcards, 30 postcards (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Postcards depicting busts, statues, and monuments of Lincoln.
      Rudin # L-5C
    - 96 postcards (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
      Postcards of Lincoln, Mary Lincoln, and various scenes.
  - Ribbons, Badges, Medals, and Tokens
    - Ribbon, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Ribbon advertising the 1860 Lincoln-Hamlin campaign.
      Rudin # L-6
    - Token and ribbon, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Artifacts promoting Lincoln's 1864 campaign.
      Rudin # L-6A
    - Badge, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Badge with Lincoln's portrait promoting his 1864 campaign.
      Rudin # L-6B
    - Ribbon, 1865; Framed (Box 21)
      Ribbon worn after Lincoln's assassination.
      Rudin # L-6C
    - Ribbon, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Mourning ribbon reading, "In Memoriam - Our Country's Martyr," worn after Lincoln's assassination.
      Rudin # L-6D
    - Badge, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Mourning ribbon reading, "In Memory of Abraham Lincoln - Died April 15, 1865."
      Rudin # L-6E
    - Ribbon, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Mourning ribbon reading, "True in Life, True in Death - Our Country Mourns the Loss of her Best Son."
      Rudin # L-6F
    - Medal, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Medal advertising the Lincoln-Johnson campaign of 1864, with jugate images of candidates in profile.
      Rudin # L-7
    - Tokens, 1860; 2 tokens (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Campaign tokens advertising Lincoln's 1860 candidacy.
      Rudin # L-7A
    - Two key chains, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      Two bicentennial memorial key chains.
  - Songs
    - Song sheet, between 1860 and 1864 (Box 10)
      Song sheet printed with lyrics to "Abe Lincoln's Union Wagon," by C. Magnus.
      Rudin # L-8
    - Songbook, 1860; Paper booklet (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Campaign songbook entitled, "The Wide-Awake Vocalist; or, Rail Splitter's Song Book."
      Rudin # L-8C
    - Song sheet, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Song sheet printed with lyrics to "The Nation Mourns."
      Rudin # L-8A
    - Song sheet, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Song sheet printed with lyrics to "President Lincoln's Funeral March."
      Rudin # L-8B
    - Song sheet, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Song sheet printed with lyrics to "Rest Noble Chieftain - Song on the Death of Abraham Lincoln."
      Rudin # L-8D
  - Miscellaneous Objects
    - Coins, 20th and 21st century; One penny in plastic enclosure; canvas bag of assorted other pennies. (Box 14)
      Lincoln penny from 1909 with sculptor's initials, V.D.B., plus a one-pound bag of assorted Lincoln pennies.
      Rudin # L-9
    - Ballot, 1860; 1 document (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Ballot from the 1860 election.
      Rudin # L-10
    - Ballot, November 8, 1864; 1 document (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Ballot from the 1864 election.
      Rudin # L-10A
    - Carte de Visite, February 9, 1864; 1 card (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Visiting card with Matthew Brady's photograph of Lincoln later used for the image on the penny.
      Rudin # L-10J
    - Invitation, March 4, 1865; 1 document (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Invitation to the Lincoln-Johnson inaugural ball.
      Rudin # L-10B
    - Order of Funeral Procession, April 19, 1865; 1 sheet (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Booklet describing the order and customs for Lincoln's funeral procession.
      Rudin # L-10F
    - Carte de Visite, April 23, 1865; 1 card (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Visiting card depicting Lincoln's funeral procession in Philadelphia.
      Rudin # L-10G
    - Stationary, April 25, 1865; 1 sheet (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Stationary with tinted letterhead depicting Lincoln's funeral procession in New York.
      Rudin # L-10H
    - Stereoview, 1865; 1 card (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Stereoview of Ford's Theater in Washington, D.C.
      Rudin # L-10D
    - Stereoview, 1865; 1 card (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Stereoview of the Customs House in Boston, Mass., displaying mourning drape after Lincoln's death.
      Rudin # L-
      Rudin # L-10E
    - Dish (Box 18)
      A milk glass souvenir dish with a split-rail pattern.
      Rudin # L-10K
    - Bust, ca. 1920 (Box 14)
      A profile bust of Lincoln made from macerated pennies.
      Rudin # L-10L
    - Relief portrait, 1865 (Box 14)
      A relief portrait of Lincoln's profile, set in its original case.
      Rudin # L-10M
    - Tile, ca. 1916 (Box 21)
      A framed ceramic pottery tile depicting an image of Lincoln.
      Rudin # L-10N
    - Engraving, April 23, 1865 (Box 14)
      A framed wooden engraving of Lincoln's image.
      Rudin # L-10P
    - Gravy boat, late 1800s (Box 15)
      A Staffordshire gravy boat depicting Lincoln delivering the Gettysburg Address.
      Rudin # L-10Q
    - Broadside, April 14, 1865; 1 large sheet (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Broadside from Ford's Theater, advertising the show the night Lincoln was shot.
      Rudin # L-10C
    - Lithograph, 1865 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      Hand-colored lithograph depicting the Lincoln Memorial.
    - Stamps, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      200th anniversary commemorative stamp and coin set.
    - Stamps, 1959, 2008, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Etching with 1-cent and 3-cent stamp, 4-cent printed stamp on note card, 2008 commemorative stamp folio sheets, 200th anniversary first day of issue stamps.
    - Stamps, 1909, 1954, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      1954 envelope with 4-cent stamps, 1940 13th amendment stamp, four 1909 2-cent stamps.
    - Stamps, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Commemorative envelopes with sheets of 4-cent, 3-cent, and 1-cent stamps
    - Stamps, 1954-1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Commemorative envelopes with 4-cent, 5-cent, and 25-cent airmail stamps.
    - Stamps, 2006-2009 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Various Lincoln stamps from St. Vincent and the Grenadines, Marshall Islands, Gabon, Rwanda, Sao Tome and Principe, Togo, Liberia, Guinea-Bissau, Democratic Republic of Congo, and 1989 World Stamp Expo.
    - Stamp and envelope, 1861 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      Postal-used Lincoln patriotic cover with three-cent stamp.
    - Stamps, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 17A)
      Forever stamps, in sheets, commemorating 150th anniversary of the Emancipation Proclamation. First Day of Issue, with USPS envelope.
    - Stamps, poster, 2013 (Folder 1)
      Forever Stamp sheet, with original print by the designer
  - Newspapers
    - Harper's Weekly, May 26, 1860 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Coverage of Lincoln's announcement that he will become a presidential candidate.
      Rudin # L-3H
    - New York Tribune, November 30, 1860 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Coverage of the South's secession from the Union.
    - Harper's Weekly, October 4, 1862 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Coverage of the Emancipation Proclamation.
      Rudin # L-3E
    - National Anti-Slavery Standard, December 6, 1862 (Box 21)
      Coverage of compensated emancipation.
      Rudin # L-3K
    - The New York Times, January 3, 1863 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Rudin # L-3F
    - The Philadelphia Inquirer, September 3, 1863 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Coverage of the Emancipation Proclamation and slavery.
      Rudin # L-3J
    - New York Tribune, March 28, 1864 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Coverage of Lincoln's amnesty proclamation.
      Rudin # L-3I
    - The New York Times, February 1, 1865 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Coverage of passage of the 13th Amendment.
      Rudin # L-3G
    - The New York Herald, April 15, 1865 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Reprint of Lincoln assassination coverage.
      Rudin # L-3
    - The New York Times, April 17, 1865 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Lincoln assassination coverage.
      Rudin # L-3A
    - The New York Times, April 19, 1865 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Rudin # L-3B
    - Harper's Weekly, May 6, 1865 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      Rudin # L-3D
- Series II. Other U.S. presidents
  - American President stamps (Box 10)
    Binder, "The Presidential First Day Cover Collection"
  - American Presidents (Box 8, Folder 16)
    Foreign stamp sheets of U.S. presidents.
  - Adams, John, 1938; Stamps (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Envelope with 4 6-cent Adams stamps, note card with stamped 6-cent stamp, 4 6-cent stamps.
  - Adams, John Office held: As member of Massachusetts Governor's Council, October 11, 1775; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 1A)
    Original 10/11/1775, correction 8/16/1776. Appointing Justices of the Inferior Court of Common Pleas. All references to King George III and Great Britain are crossed out.
    Rudin # P-1
  - Adams, John Quincy Office held: While representing Massachusetts in the House of Representatives Addressee: Solomon Lincoln, Josiah Brigham, Joseph Richards Writer's location: Quincy, MA, October 19, 1840; Pages: 1 1/2 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    Conduct in campaigning for the Presidency.
    Rudin # P-2
  - Arthur, Chester Office held: Customs Collector for the Port of New York Addressee: Commander of the USS Alaska Writer's location: New York, September 25, 1876; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Smuggling of Wines, Cigars and Silks.
    Rudin # P-3
  - Buchanan, James Office held: As Secretary of State Writer's location: Washington, D.C., March 10, 1845; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Announces his appointment as Secretary of State by President Polk. Dated his first day in office.
    Rudin # P-4
  - Buchanan, James Office held: As Secretary of State Addressee: John Wadman Writer's location: Washington, D.C., December 10, 1847; Pages: 4 (3 pages blank) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Seeking the 1848 nomination for President.
    Rudin # P-5
  - Buchanan, James Office held: No elective office held Addressee: John M. Jones Writer's location: Wheatland near Lancaster, PA, December 5, 1851; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Supporting the wrong candidate for office might damage his chances for the 1852 Presidential nomination.
    Rudin # P-6
  - Buchanan, James Office held: No elective office held Addressee: Barnabas Bates, Assistant Postmaster Writer's location: Wheatland near Lancaster, PA, June 14, 1852; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    After failing to gain the Democratic Presidential nomination.
    Rudin # P-7
  - Buchanan, James Office held: As President Addressee: William L. Marcy, Secretary of State Writer's location: Washington, D.C., March 5, 1857; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    On his first full day as President.
    Rudin # P-8
  - Bush, George, H.W. Office held: As President Addressee: "Dr. Ray S. Cline - Chairman, U.S. Global Strategy Council" Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", March 21, 1990; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Discusses our policy toward China.
    Rudin # P-9
  - Bush, George, H.W. Office held: As President Addressee: Giulio Andreotti, Prime Minister of Italy Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", March 22, 1990; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    "I valued our substantive discussions - our transatlantic ties have never been better".
    Rudin # P-10
  - Bush, George H.W. Office held: As President Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", January 16, 1991; Pages: 3 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Announcing the beginning of the 1991 war against Iraq. From the Forbes Collection - Part 3.
    Rudin # P-11
  - Bush, George W., January 17, 1991; Newspaper (Box 13, Folder 8)
    New York Times coverage of Iraq war.
  - Bush, George, H.W. Office held: As Ex President Addressee: Ron Weekes Writer's location: Kennebunkport, ME, July 16, 1993; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Describing his state of mind and the goal of the Presidency.
    Rudin # P-12
  - Bush, George, H.W. Office held: As Ex President Addressee: Daniel Patrick Moynihan, Senator Writer's location: Houston, TX, June 12, 1996; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Discusses Most Favored Nation Trade Status for China.
    Rudin # P-13
  - Bush, George H.W. Office held: As Ex President Addressee: Melville & Lizanne Chapin Writer's location: Houston, TX, November 17, 1998; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    On the gubernatorial elections of his two sons.
    Rudin # P-14
  - Bush, George, H.W. Office held: As Ex President Addressee: Dear Helen Writer's location: Houston, TX, July 14, 2000; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Not interested in writing a memoir, "Thanks for your support of George W. He's a good man and he won't let you down."
    Rudin # P-15
  - Bush, George W. Office held: As Governor of Texas Addressee: Bill Christiansen Writer's location: Austin, TX, March 2, 1996; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    "every Texan has a key role in making Texas a greater state".
    Rudin # P-16
  - Bush, George W. Office held: As Governor of Texas Addressee: Ralph Benson Writer's location: Austin, TX, October 5, 1998; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Concerning running for President.
    Rudin # P-17
  - Bush, George W. Office held: As Governor of Texas Addressee: Bill Christiansen Writer's location: Austin, TX, August 23, 1999; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    About the direction of our youth and the teaching of morals and values.
    Rudin # P-18
  - Bush, George, W. Office held: As Governor of Texas Addressee: Chip Freundt Writer's location: Austin, TX, August 22, 2000; Pages: 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Describes his feelings for his father.
    Rudin # P-19
  - Bush, George W., 2001; Newspapers (Box 20)
    Two newspapers on 9/11 and the Bush administration.
  - Bush, George, W. Office held: As President Addressee: "Kevin C. Jenkins, Mayor Rhinelander, Wisconsin" Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", April 2, 2003; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    "We can create an environment where small business flourishes and Americans... can find jobs".
    Rudin # P-20
  - Carter, Jimmy Office held: As Ex President Addressee: Bruce Becker Writer's location: Plains, GA, No Date; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Re: Religion.
    Rudin # P-21
  - Carter, Jimmy Office held: As Candidate for President Addressee: Jimmy Carter, ca. 1976; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Notes from speech writer Pat Anderson.
    Rudin # P-22
  - Carter, Jimmy Office held: As Candidate for President Addressee: Al Smith Dinner Writer's location: New York, 1976; Pages: 15 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    "Two weeks before Election Day 1976." Draft of speech for Al Smith Dinner.
    Rudin # P-23
  - Carter, Jimmy Office held: As President-Elect Addressee: Congressman Del Clausson Writer's location: Washington, D.C., January 12, 1977; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Increasing the effectiveness of the Executive Branch.
    Rudin # P-24
  - Carter, Jimmy Office held: As President Addressee: Robert P. Griffin, Senator Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", May 12, 1978; Pages: 2 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Encourages the sale of military aircraft to Israel, Egypt and Saudi Arabia.
    Rudin # P-25
  - Carter, Jimmy Office held: As President Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", March 26, 1979; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Excerpt from Carter's speech as the Camp David Peace Treaty was signed.
    Rudin # P-26
  - Carter, Jimmy Office held: As President Addressee: Daniel Patrick Moynihan, Senator Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", May 9, 1979; Pages: 2 1/3 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Re: The Salt Treaty.
    Rudin # P-27
  - Carter, Jimmy, 1982
    "Keeping Faith. Memoirs of a President" Bantam Books, New York, NY. Signed copy. See separated material below.
    Rudin # P-28
  - Carter, Jimmy Office held: As Ex President Writer's location: New York, May 21, 1982; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Contract for "Keeping Faith" between President Carter and Bantam Books.
    Rudin # P-29
  - Carter, Jimmy Office held: As Ex President Addressee: Robert Garcia, Congressman Writer's location: Atlanta, GA, October 8, 1982; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Re: Creating a national holiday on Martin Luther King's Birthday.
    Rudin # P-30
  - Carter, Jimmy Office held: As Ex President Addressee: Larry Ervin Clevenger Writer's location: Plains, GA ?, February 25, 1991; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Will not run for President in 1992. Will dedicate himself to humane issues and The Carter Center.
    Rudin # P-31
  - Cleveland, Grover Office held: As President Addressee: John E. Develin Writer's location: "Executive Mansion Washington, D.C.", April 29, 1885; Pages: 3 1/2 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    The disappointments, pressures and frustrations of being a new President.
    Rudin # P-32
  - Cleveland, Grover Office held: Period between his two Presidencies Addressee: Don M. Dickinson, Former Postmaster General Writer's location: New York, May 10, 1889; Pages: 3 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Though pleased by "the cheers of the people for me...I am enjoying my release from official care more than I can tell you".
    Rudin # P-33
  - Cleveland, Grover Office held: Period between his two Presidencies Addressee: Henry Watterson Writer's location: New York, March 20, 1890; Pages: 4 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    His feelings about having been President and what the future of the Party may be. Includes a large etching.1
    Rudin # P-34
  - Cleveland, Grover Office held: Period between his two Presidencies Addressee: Charles Krichbaum, President Young Men's Democratic Club of Canton, Ohio Writer's location: New York, November 28, 1890; Pages: 5 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    Government must merit the people's trust. (With an unrelated letter to Krichbaum from Tom L. Johnson).
    Rudin # P-35
  - Cleveland, Grover Office held: As President (Second Term) Addressee: Reverend William Neal Cleveland (His brother) Writer's location: "Executive Mansion Washington, D.C.", June 7, 1896; Pages: 4 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    Discusses how he might help financially in a difficult family situation.
    Rudin # P-36
  - Clinton, William Office held: As Governor of Arkansas Addressee: Jim Coish Writer's location: Little Rock, AK, April 29, 1987; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Prepares for a possible 1988 Presidential run.
    Rudin # P-37
  - Clinton, William Office held: As Governor of Arkansas Addressee: "Sandra Adair Vaughn, Virginia Board of Education" Writer's location: Little Rock, AK, April 29, 1987; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Urges the hiring of black teachers.
    Rudin # P-38
  - Clinton, William Office held: As President Addressee: "William H. Natcher, Congressman - Chairman of the Comm. on Appropriations" Writer's location: "The White House Washington, D.C.", July 1, 1993; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Promoting foreign policy measures in support of a democratic Russia.
    Rudin # P-39